[Girl Humming]
[Humming Continues]
[Girl Sighs]
[Continues Humming]
[Humming Continues]
[Ticking]
[GirlSighs]
[Humming Continues]
[Girl]
Bing.
[Continues Humming]
[Girl Murmurs]
[Girl Giggling]
[Girl Hums, Rips Paper]
[Birds Chirping]
[Woman Narrating]
Maycomb was a tired, old town,
even in 1932
when l first knew it.
Some how it was hotter then.
Men's stiff collars wilted
by 9:00 in the morning.
Ladies bathed before noon,
after their 3:00 naps...
and by night fall
were like soft tea cakes...
with frostings of sweat
and sweet talcum.
The day was 24 hours long,
but it seemed longer.
There was no hurry,
for there was nowhere to go...
and nothing to buy:;
no money to buy it with.
Although Maycomb County
had recently been told...
that it had nothing to fear
but fear itself.
That summer
I was six years old.
- Good morning, Mr. Cunningham.
- Good morning, miss.
My daddy's getting dressed.
Would you like me to call hI'm for you?
- I don't care to bother.
- Why, it's no bother, Mr. Cunningham.
He'll be happy to see you.
Atticus!
Atticus?
It's Mr. Cunningham.
- Good morning, Walter.
- Good morning, Mr. Finch.
I didn't want to bother you none.
I brung you these here hickory nuts
as part of my entailment.
Well, I thank you. The collards
we had last week were delicious.
Well, Morning.
Morning.
Scout, I think maybe, uh,
next time Mr. Cunningham comes,
you better not call me.
- I thought you'd want to thank him.
- Oh, I do.
I think it embarrasses him
to be thanked.
Why does he bring you
all this stuff?
He's paying me for some legal work
I did for him.
Why does he pay you like this?
That's the only way he can.
He has no money.
- Is he poor?
- Yes.
Are we poor?
We are, indeed.
Are we as poor
as the Cunninghams?
No, not exactly.
Cunninghams are
country folks, farmers.
- The crash hit them the hardest.
- [ Screen Door Squeaks ]
Scout, call your brother.
[ Scout ]
Atticus? Jem's up in the tree.
He says he won't come down
until you agree to play football
for the Methodists.
Jem?
Son, why don't you come down out
of there now and have your breakfast.
Calpurnia has a good one.
Hot biscuits.
[ Jem ] Not 'til you agree
to play football for the Methodists.
Oh, son, I can't do that.
I'm too old to get out there.
After all,
I'm the only father you have.
Wouldn't want me to get
my head knocked off, would you?
I ain't comin' down.
Suit yourself.
[ Woman ]
Good morning.
Good morning,
Miss Maudie.
- What's going on over there?
- I'm having a terrible time,
Miss Maudie.
Jem's stayin' up in the tree
until Atticus agrees to play
football for the Methodists.
Atticus says
he's too old.
Every time I'm wantin'
to do something, he's too old.
He's too old for anything!
[ Maudie ]
He can do plenty of things.
You be good, children.
Mind Cal.
- Morning, Maudie.
- Morning, Atticus.
He won't let me have a gun,
and he'll only play
touch football with me, never tackle.
He can make somebody's will
so airtight, you can't break it.
You count your blessings
and stop complaining, both of you.
Thank your stars
he has the sense to act his age.
- Jem, he is pretty old.
- I can't help that.
Hey.
Hey, yourself.
I'm Charles Baker Harris.
I can read.
You got anything needs readin',
I can do it.
How old are you?
Four and a half?
- Goin' on seven.
- No wonder then.
Scout's been readin'
since she was born,
and she don't start school
'til next month.
You look right puny
for goin' on seven.
I'm little, but I'm old.
Folks call me Dill.
I'm from Meridian, Mississippi.
I'm spending two weeks next door
with my Aunt Stephanie.
My mama worked for a photographer
in Meridian.
She entered my picture
in the "Beautiful Child" contest
and won five dollars on me.
She give the money to me, and I went
to the picture show 20 times with it.
- Our mama's dead, but we got a daddy.
- Where's your daddy?
- I haven't got one.
- Is he dead?
[ Dill ]
No.
Well, if he's not dead,
you've got one, haven't you?
- [ Screen Door Squeaks ]
- Hush, Scout.
[ Softly ]
What did I do? What did I do?
Dill, this is Calpurnia.
Pleased to know you, Dill.
[ Dill ]
Pleased to know you.
My daddy owns
the L&N Railroad.
He's gonna let me run the engine
all the way to New Orleans.
Is that so?
- [ Dill ]
He says I can invite anybody--
- Shh.
[ Footsteps ]
There goes the meanest man
that ever took a breath of life.
Why is he the meanest man?
Well, for one thing,
he has a boy named Boo...
that he keeps chained to a bed
in the house over yonder.
Come on.
See? He lives over there.
Boo only comes out
at night...
when you're asleep
and it's pitch dark.
When you wake up at night,
you can hear him.
Once I heard hI'm scratching
on our screen door,
but he was gone
by the time Atticus got there.
Wonder what he does in there.
Wonder what he looks like.
Well...
judging from his tracks,
he's about
six and a half feet tall.
He eats raw squirrels
and all the cats he can catch.
There's a long, jagged scar
that runs across his face.
His teeth are yellow and rotten.
His eyes are popped,
and he drools most of the time.
Oh, I don't believe you.
Dill, what are you doing here?
My Lord, Aunt Stephanie!
You almost gave me a heart attack!
Dill, I don't want you playing
around that house over there.
A maniac lives there,
and he's dangerous.
See? I was trying to warn him
about Boo, but he wouldn't believe me.
You better believe him,
Mr. Dill Harris.
Tell hI'm about the time Boo
tried to kill his papa.
I was standing in my yard
when his mama come out yelling,
"He's killing us all!"
Turned out that Boo was sitting
in the living room cutting up
the paper for his scrapbook,
and when his daddy come by,
he reached over with his scissors,
stabbed hI'm in his leg, pulled them out
and went right on cutting the paper.
They wanted to send him
to an asylum,
but his daddy said,
"No Radley is going to any asylum."
So they locked hI'm up
in the basement of the courthouse...
'til he nearly died of the damp...
and his daddy
brought hI'm back home.
There he is to this day,
sitting over there with his scissors.
Lord knows what
he's doing or thinking.
[ Shouting ]
Six, seven, eight,
- [ Bell Tolling ]
- nine, ten!
[ Tolling Continues ]
Come on, Scout!
It's 5:00!
- Where you going?
- Time to meet Atticus.
- Why do you call your daddy Atticus?
- 'Cause Jem does.
- Why does he?
- I don't know.
He just started to
ever since he began talking.
[ Spits ]
Wait. Stop.
- Miss Dubose is on her porch.
- [ Groans ]
Listen, no matter what she says to you,
don't answer her back.
There's a Confederate pistol
in her lap under her shawl,
and she'll kill you
quick as look at you.
Come on.
- Hey, Miss Dubose.
- Don't you say "hey" to me,
you ugly girl!
You say,
"Good afternoon, Miss Dubose."
You come over here
when I'm talking to you.
- You come over here, I said!
- Hi, Atticus.
- [ Dubose Continues Shouting ]
- Atticus, this is Dill.
He's Miss Stephanie's nephew.
[ Dubose ] Don't your daddy
teach you to respect old people?
You come back here,
Jean Louise Finch!
Good afternoon, Miss Dubose.
My, you look like
a picture this afternoon.
[ Scout Whispers ]
He don't say a picture of what.
My goodness gracious,
look at your flowers.
Have you ever seen
anything more beautiful?
Miss Dubose,
the gardens at Bellingrath
have nothing to compare...
with your flowers.
I don't think they're
as nice as last year.
He gets her interested in something nice
so she forgets to be mean.
Your yard is going to be
the showplace of this town.
Well, grand seeing you,
Miss Dubose.
"l had two cats...
which I brought ashore...
on my first raft.
And I had a dog."
Atticus, do you think Boo Radley
ever really comes and looks
in my window at night?
- Jem says he does. This afternoon
when we were over by their house--
- Scout...
I told you and Jem
to leave those poor people alone.
I want you to stay away
from their house...
and stop tormenting them.
Yes, sir.
That's all the reading
for tonight, honey. It's getting late.
- What time is it?
- 8:30.
May I see your watch?
"To Atticus,
my beloved husband."
Atticus, Jem says this watch
is gonna belong to hI'm someday.
- That's right.
- Why?
Well...
it's customary...
for the boy to have
his father's watch.
What are you gonna give me?
I don't know that I have
much else of value that belongs to me.
But there's a pearl necklace,
there's a ring that
belonged to your mother.
I put them away,
and they're to be yours.
- Good night, Scout.
- Good night.
- [ Atticus ] Good night, Jem.
- [ Jem ] Good night.
- Jem?
- [ Jem ] Yes?
- [ Sighs ]
How old was I when Mama died?
- Two.
- How old were you?
- Six.
- Old as I am now?
- Mm-hmm.
- Was Mama pretty?
[ Scout ]
Was Mama nice?
[ Jem ]
Mm-hmm.
- Did you love her?
- Yes.
- Did I love her?
- Mm-hmm.
- Do you miss her?
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
- [ Man ] Evening, Atticus.
- Good evening, Judge.
Rather warm, isn't it?
Yes, indeed.
How's Mrs. Taylor?
She's fine.
Fine, thank you.
Atticus, you've heard
about Tom Robinson.
Yes, sir.
Grand jury will get around
to charging hI'm tomorrow.
I was thinking about appointing you
to take his case.
Now I realize you're very busy
these days with your practice.
And your children need
a great deal of your time.
Yes, sir.
I'll take the case.
I'll send a boy over for you tomorrow
when his hearing comes up.
Well... I'll see you tomorrow,
Atticus.
Yes, sir.
And thank you.
Hey, Jem, I bet you a "Grey Ghost"
against two "Tom Swifts"...
you wouldn't go any farther
than Boo Radley's gate.
Aw.
- Scared to, ain't you?
- I ain't scared.
I go past Boo Radley's house
nearly every day of my life.
- Always running.
- You hush up, Scout.
- Come on, Dill!
- Me first! Me first!
- You gotta let Dill be first.
- No! Me, me, me!
- [ Dill ] Oh, let her be first.
All right, get in!
- Hurry up!
- All right.
- You ready?
- Uh-huh. Let her go.
Scout!
Scout, get away from there!
Scout, come on!
Don't just lie there!
Get up!
Come on, Scout.
Run for your life, Scout!
Come on, Dill!
[ Panting ]
Now who's a coward?
You tell them about this back
in Meridian County, Mr. Dill Harris.
I'll tell you what let's do.
Let's go down to the courthouse and see
the room that they locked Boo up in.
My aunt says it's bat-infested,
and he nearly died from the mildew.
Come on! I bet they got chains
and instruments of torture down there.
Come on!
- Jem Finch?
- Yes, sir?
If you're looking for your daddy,
he's inside the courthouse.
-Thank you, sir, but we're not looking--
-Thank you, Mr. Townsend.
What's your daddy doing
in the courthouse?
He's a lawyer,
and he has a case.
The grand jury is charging
his client today.
I heard something about it last night
when Judge Taylor came over.
- Let's go watch.
- No, Dill.
- He wouldn't like that. Dill!
- Dill!
[ Jem, Hushed ]
Dill, wait a minute.
Shh.
- [ Typing ]
- Is that the courtroom?
[ Whispers ]
Yeah. Shh.
- I can't see anything.
- Shh.
Y'all lift me up
so I can see what's going on.
- All right.
- Make a saddle, Scout.
Not much is happenin'.
The judge looks like
he's asleep.
[ Groaning ]
I see your daddy
and a colored man.
- The colored man--
- Shh, shh.
The colored man looks to me
like he's cryin'.
- [ Man ] I seen hI'm with Mayella.
- I wonder what he's done
to cry about?
What's going on?
There's a whole lot of men
sittin' together on one side,
and one man keeps pointin'
at the colored man and yellin'.
They're taking
the colored man away.
- Where's Atticus?
- [ Phone Ringing ]
[ Dill ]
I can't see your daddy now either.
- I wonder where in the world--
- Scout, Jem.
What in the world
are you doing here?
[ Jem ]
Hello, Atticus.
What are you doing here?
We came down to find out where
Boo Radley was locked up.
We wanted to see the bats.
I want you all
back home right away.
- Yes, sir.
- Run along now.
I'll see you there for dinner.
Hey, howdy, Cap'n.
Mr. Ewell.
Cap'n, I'm real sorry
they picked you...
to defend that nigger
that raped my Mayella.
I don't know why I didn't kill him
myself instead of going to the sheriff.
I'd have saved you and the sheriff
and the taxpayers lots of trouble.
Excuse me. I'm busy.
Hey, Cap'n, somebody told me
just now that they thought...
that you believed Tom Robinson's story
agin ourn.
You know what I said?
[ Laughs ] I said,
"You wrong, man. You dead wrong!
Mr. Finch ain't taking
his story against ourn."
Well, they was wrong,
wasn't they?
I've been appointed
to defend Tom Robinson.
Now that he's been charged,
that's what I intend to do.
- You taking his story--
- If you'll excuse me, Mr. Ewell.
What kind of man are you?
You got children of your own.
[ Radio ]
[ Dill Whispering ]
Hey, Jem! Jem?
I think we ought to stay right here
in Miss Stephanie's yard.
You don't have to come along...
Angel May.
What are you gonna do?
[ Hushed ] Gonna look in a window
at the Radley house...
and see if we can get
a look at Boo Radley!
Come on, Dill.
- Jem, please, I'm scared.
- Go home if you're scared!
I swear, Scout, you act
more like a girl all the time.
- Come on, Dill.
- Wait for me. I'm coming.
Shh.
We'll go around back...
and crawl under the fence
at the rear of the lot.
- I don't believe we can
be seen from there.
- [ Thud, Squeaking ]
[ Squeaking Continues ]
Come on.
[ Whispers ]
Hold it up for me.
Shh.
Don't make a sound.
[ Gate Squeaks ]
Spit on it.
[ Spitting ]
All right.
[ Gate Squeaks ]
- [ Scout ] Jem.
- Shh. Spit some more.
[ Spitting ]
[ Spitting Continues ]
All right.
Come on.
[ Step Creaks ]
[ Porch Creaks ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Whimpers ]
Hurry. Hurry.
Hurry!
[ Material Rips ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Whispering ]
Scout! Scout!
[ Dog Barking ]
[ Barking Continues ]
Quick. Come on.
[ All Panting,
Dill Coughing ]
- Shh!
- [ Continues Coughing ]
- Quiet.
- Shh.
[ Panting ]
- What are you gonna do for pants, Jem?
- I don't know.
- [ Continues Panting ]
- [ Screen Door Squeaks ]
[ Aunt Stephanie ]
Dill? Dill?
You come on in now.
- Shh.
- I better go.
- [ Aunt Stephanie ] Dill?
- Coming, Aunt Stephanie!
- [ Screen Door Squeaks ]
- So long. I'll see you next summer.
- So long.
- [ Aunt Stephanie ] Dill!
- I'm comin'!
I'm going back
after my pants.
Please, Jem.
Come on in the house.
I can't go in
without my pants.
- Then I'm going to call Atticus.
- No, you're not.
Now, listen. Atticus ain't never
whipped me since I can remember,
and I plan to keep it that way.
- Then I'm going with you.
- You ain't. You stay right here.
I'll be back
before you can count to ten.
Jem.
One. Two.
Three.
- Four.
- [ Atticus ] Jem?
Scout?
Come on in.
- [ Screen Door Squeaks, Door Closes ]
- Five.
Six.
Seven.
Eight.
Nine.
Ten.
Eleven.
Twelve.
Thirteen.
- Fourteen.
- [ Gunshot ]
[ Dog Barking ]
[ Clattering,
Barking Continues ]
Jem!
- [ Door Opens, Closes ]
- Shh.
[ Barking Continues ]
[ Aunt Stephanie Yelling ]
What was that? What is it?
What happened?
What's goin' on?
What is it?
Atticus, what is it?
Will somebody please tell me
what's goin' on?
Uh, Mr. Radley...
shot at a prowler out
in his collard patch.
A prowler?
Oh, Maudie!
Whoever it was
won't be back anytime soon.
Mr. Radley must have scared them
out of their wits.
- Good night. Good night.
- Good night, Atticus.
Oh, scared the living daylights
out of me.
A prowler?
He said a prowler?
Come on now.
The excitement's over.
Time for bed.
Scout. Jem.
[ Maudie ]
Morning.
Good morning,
Miss Maudie.
- Morning, Calpurnia.
- Morning, Maudie.
Came to see if Jean Louise is ready
for her first day of school.
- [ Cal ] Scout!
- Good morning, Miss Maudie.
- You ready too?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Scout!
What are you gonna do this morning
with both children at school?
I don't know,
and that's the truth.
I was thinking
about that just now.
Scout!
Scout? Scout!
Did you hear me, Scout?
Now hurry.
[ Jem Laughs ]
Hey, look at Scout!
Shh.
- Come on in here, Scout.
- [ Stifling Laughter ]
Have your breakfast.
I think your dress
is mighty becomin', honey.
[ Cal ] Don't go tugging
at that dress, Scout.
You want to have it all wrinkled
before you even get to school?
I still don't see why I have
to wear a darn old dress.
- You'll get used to it.
- I'm ready!
Oh, Jem. Jem.
It's half an hour
before school starts.
Sit right down
and wait for your sister.
- Hurry up, Scout.
- I'm  trying to.
[ Jem ] Come on! It's your first day.
You want to be late?
- I'm ready.
- [ Jem ] Let's go!
Bye.
Bye, everybody!
[ Chuckling ]
[ Shouting ]
Darn you,
Walter Cunningham!
[ Children Shouting ]
- [ Children ] Come on, Walter!
- Come on, Walter!
- [ Jem ] Scout!
Cut that out!
What do you think you're doing?
[ Grunting ]
He made me start off
on the wrong foot!
I was trying to explain
to that darn lady teacher...
why he didn't have no money
for his lunch, and she got sore at me!
Stop it! Stop it!
Is your daddy Mr. Walter Cunningham
from Old Sarum?
Come home and have dinner
with us, Walter.
We'd be glad to have you.
Our daddy is a friend
of your daddy's.
[ Sighs ]
Scout here is crazy.
She won't fight you no more.
[ Atticus ]
I hope that's a dinner that you enjoy.
Yes, sir. I don't know
when I've had a roast.
We've been having squirrels
and rabbits lately.
My pa and I go hunting
in our spare time.
- You got a gun of your own?
- [ Walter ] Uh-huh.
- [ Jem ] How long you had a gun?
- Oh, a year or so.
- Can I have the syrup, please?
- Certainly, son.
Cal, will you bring in
the syrup dish, please?
Yes, sir.
How old were you when you got
your first gun, Atticus?
Thirteen or fourteen.
I remember when my daddy
gave me that gun.
He told me that I should never point
at anything in the house...
and that he'd rather
I shoot at tin cans in the backyard.
But he said that sooner
or later he supposed...
the temptation to go after birds
would be too much...
and that I could shoot all the blue jays
I wanted, if I could hit 'em;
but to remember it was a sin
to kill a mockingbird.
- Why?
- [ Atticus ] Well, I reckon...
because mockingbirds
don't do anything...
but make music
for us to enjoy.
Don't eat people's gardens.
Don't nest in the corn cribs.
They don't do one thing but just
sing their hearts out for us.
How'd you like school, Scout?
All right.
Oh, thank you, Cal.
That's for Walter.
- What in the Sam Hill
are you doing, Wa--
- [ Tapping ]
But, Atticus, he's gone
and drowned his dinner in syrup,
- and now he's pouring it all over--
- [ Cal ] Scout.
- What?
- Come out here. I want to talk to you.
That boy is your company.
If he wants to eat that tablecloth,
you'll let him.
If you can't act fit
to eat like folks,
you can just sit here
and eat in the kitchen.
[ Atticus ]
Scout.
- [ Mumbling Softly ]
- Scout, what in the world
has got into you?
- [ Repeating ] I'm not going back.
- Now, now.
Atticus, I'm not going back
to school anymore.
Now, Scout,
it's just the first day.
I don't care.
Everything went wrong.
The teacher got mad
as the devil at me...
and said you were teaching me
to read all wrong and to stop it,
then acted like a fool and tried to give
Walter Cunningham a quarter...
when everybody knows Cunninghams
won't take nothin' from nobody.
Any fool could have told her that.
Well... maybe she's just nervous.
After all, it's her first day
teaching school and being new here.
- Oh, Atticus--
- Now, wait a minute.
If you learn
this single trick, Scout,
you'll get along a lot better
with all kinds of folks.
You never really
understand a person...
until you consider things
from his point of view.
Sir?
Until you climb inside of his skin
and walk around in it.
But if I keep going to school,
we can't ever read anymore.
Scout...
do you know what
a compromise is?
Bending the law?
Uh... no.
It's an agreement reached
by mutual consent.
Now... here's
the way it works.
You concede the necessity
of going to school,
we'll keep right on reading
the same every night...
just as we always have.
That a bargain?
[ Adult Scout Narrating ]
There just didn't seem to be...
anyone or anything
Atticus couldn't explain.
Though it wasn't a talent
that would arouse the admiration
of any of our friends,
Jem and I had to admit
he was very good at that.
- [ Dog Growling ]
- But that was all
he was good at... we thought.
- See? There he is.
- [ Growling Continues ]
[ Snarling, Growling ]
[ Snarling, Growling Continue ]
Scout, Jem,
come on inside.
- [ Snarling Continues ]
- Come on! Come on. Get in.
Mr. Finch?
This is Cal.
I swear to God, there's a mad dog
down the street a piece.
He's coming this way!
[ Car Approaching ]
There he is.
He's got it, all right,
Mr. Finch.
Stay inside, son.
Keep them in there, Cal.
He's within range, Heck.
- [ Dog Snarling ]
- Take him, Mr. Finch.
- Oh, no, Mr. Tate! He can't shoot!
- Don't waste time, Heck.
He's got to be killed
before he starts runnin'.
Look where he is. I can't shoot
that well, and you know it.
[ Atticus ]
I haven't shot a gun in years.
I'd feel mighty comfortable
if you did now.
[ Dog Snarling, Barking ]
[ Snarling, Barking Continue ]
[ Growling ]
[ Growling Continues ]
- Don't go near that dog. He's just
as dangerous dead as alive.
- Yes, sir.
- Atticus?
- Yes, son.
- Nothin'.
- What's the matter, boy?
Can't you talk?
- Didn't you know your daddy is
the best shot in this county?
- Oh, hush, Heck.
Let's get back to town.
- Remember now, don't go near that dog.
- Yes, sir.
I'll send Zeebo out right away
to pick him up.
[ Jem Shouts ]
Hey, Atticus, can we go with ya?
- Can we, please?
- Huh, can we?
I have to go to the country on business,
and you'll just get tired.
Oh, no, not me.
I won't get tired.
Well, you promise to stay in the car
while I talk to Helen Robinson?
- Mm-hmm.
- And not nag me about leaving
if you get tired?
- Huh-uh.
- All right, climb in.
- Who's Helen Robinson?
- She's the wife of the man
I'm defending.
[ Brakes Squeak ]
- Good evening, David.
- Good evening.
- Good evening, Helen.
- Evening, Mr. Finch.
- I came over to tell you
about my visit with Tom.
- Yes, sir.
And to let you know
that I got a postponement of the trial.
[ Atticus Continues, lndistinct ]
[ Leaves Rustling ]
Would you tell my daddy
to come out here, please?
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
You nigger lover.
No need to be afraid of him, son.
He's all bluff.
[ Starts Engine ]
[ Ewell ]
Nigger lover!
There's a lot of ugly things
in this world, son.
I wish I could
keep 'em all away from you.
That's never possible.
Cal, if you wait 'til I get Scout
in bed, I'll drive you home.
Yes, sir.
Jem, do you mind stayin' here with Scout
'til I get Cal home?
- No, sir.
- Night, Jem.
Night, Cal.
[ Car Door Shuts ]
[ Engine Starts, Car Departs ]
[ Rustling ]
[ Rustling Continues ]
[ Bird Screeching ]
Atticus! Atticus!
Atticus!
[ Sighs ]
[ Bird Screeches ]
[ Banging, Creaking ]
[ Banging, Creaking Continue ]
[ Footsteps ]
[ Banging, Creaking ]
[ Continues Banging, Creaking ]
[ Bird Screeches ]
[ Banging ]
[ Banging, Creaking ]
[ Banging Continues ]
[ Bird Screeches ]
[ Adult Scout ]
Atticus had promised me
he would wear me out...
if he ever heard
of me fightin' anymore.
I was far too old and too big
for such childish things.
And the sooner I learned to hold in,
the better off everybody would be.
I soon forgot.
Cecil Jacobs made me forget.
Oh, what is it, Scout?
Atticus, do you defend niggers?
- Don't say "nigger," Scout.
- I didn't say it.
Cecil Jacobs did.
That's why I had to fight him.
Scout,
I don't want you fightin'.
I had to, Atticus.
- He--
- I don't care what the reasons are.
- I forbid you to fight.
- Yes.
Anyway... I'm simply defending
a Negro, Tom Robinson.
Now, Scout,
there are some things that...
you're not old enough
to understand just yet.
There's been some high talk
around town...
to the effect that I shouldn't do much
about defending this man.
If you shouldn't be defending him,
then why are you doing it?
For a number of reasons.
The main one is that,
if I didn't,
I couldn't hold
my head up in town.
I couldn't even tell you or Jem...
not to do something again.
[ Softly ]
Scout.
You're gonna hear some
ugly talk about this in school.
But I want you
to promise me one thing:
That you won't get
into fights over it,
no matter what
they say to you.
- [ Car Approaching ]
- Yes, sir.
[ Car Engine ldling ]
- What are you doing?
- I'm walking like an Egyptian.
- We were studyin' about 'em in school.
- [ Engine Stops ]
Teacher says we wouldn't
be no place without 'em.
Is that so?
Cradle of civilization. They invented
embalming and toilet paper.
That's wrong, Scout.
- You do your feet this way.
- Look, Jem.
Look, the boy wears hair
in front of his eyebrows like you do.
Yeah, and the girl
wears bangs like you.
[ Whispers ]
These are of us.
[ Children Running ]
[ Softly ]
Jem, you awake?
- Go back to bed.
- I can't go to sleep.
Go back to bed.
[ Scout ]
What you got in the box?
Nothin'. Go back to bed.
Come on.
If I show you, will you swear
never to tell anybody?
I swear.
Cross your heart.
[ Watch Ticking ]
[ Ticking Continues ]
- [ Ticking ]
- [ Jem ] I found all of these...
in the knothole of that old tree
at different times.
[ Softly ]
This is a spelling medal.
You know they used to award these
in school to spelling winners...
before we were born.
And another time,
I found this.
[ Ticking ]
[ Ticking Continues ]
And this.
Scout...
you know somethin' else I never told you
about that night I went back...
- to the Radley house?
- "Somethin' else"?
You never told me anything
about that night.
Well...
the first time when I was
gettin' out of my britches?
- Uh-huh.
- Well, they was all in a tangle,
and I couldn't get 'em loose.
Well, when I went back, though,
they were folded
across the fence,
sort of like
they was expectin' me.
[ Watch Ticking ]
[ Adult Scout ]
It was to be a long time...
before Jem and I talked
about Boo again.
School finally ended
and summer came...
and so did Dill.
- Good mornin'.
- Good mornin'. My, you're up...
mighty bright and early.
Ooh, I been up since 4:00.
- [ Cal ] 4:00?
- Oh, yes, I always get up at 4:00.
It's in my blood.
My daddy was a railroad man
'til he got rich.
Now he flies airplanes.
One of these days,
he's just gonna swoop
down here at Maycomb,
pick me up and take me
for a ride.
Who's that in the car
with Sheriff Tate?
Tom Robinson, son.
Where's he been?
In the Abbottsville jail.
- Why?
- The sheriff thought
he'd be safer there.
They're bringin' him
back here tonight...
because his trial
is tomorrow.
[ Crickets Chirping ]
[ Knocking ]
- Well, good evenin', Heck.
- Good evenin', Mr. Finch.
Come in.
The news has gotten around
the county about my bringin'
Tom Robinson back to the jail.
I, uh, heard there might be trouble
from that bunch out at Old Sarum.
Cal, if I need you to stay here tonight,
can you do it?
- Yes, sir, I can.
- Thank you.
[ Dishes Clattering ]
I think you better
count on stayin'.
Yes, sir.
[ Door Opens, Shuts ]
[ Car Door Opens, Shuts ]
[ Engine Starts,
Car Departs ]
- What's goin' on?
- Shh. Go back to sleep.
- [ Scout ] What's goin' on?
- Shh.
[ Jem Whispers ]
Hey, there's his car.
[ Whispering ]
There he is over there.
No, Scout, don't go to him.
He might not like it.
I just wanted to see where he was
and what he was up to.
He's all right.
Let's go back home.
Come on.
[ Cars Approaching ]
[ Brakes Squeaking ]
[ Engines Stop ]
- He in there, Mr. Finch?
- He is.
He's asleep.
Don't wake him.
You know what we want.
Get aside from that door,
Mr. Finch.
Walter...
I think you oughta turn
right around and go back home.
- Heck Tate's around here somewhere.
- [ Man ] No, he ain't!
Heck and his bunch is out in Old Sarum,
lookin' for us.
[ Man #2 ] We knowed he was,
so we come in this other way.
- You ain't thought
about that, had you, Mr. Finch?
- [ Atticus ] I thought about it.
- I can't see Atticus.
- [ Atticus ]
Well, that changes things some.
[ Scout ]
Atticus.
- Hey, Atticus.
- Jem, go home.
Take Scout and Dill
home with you.
- Son, I said go home.
- No, sir.
- I'll send him home.
- Don't you touch him!
Let him go!
That'll do, Scout.
Ain't nobody gonna
do Jem that way!
You get 'em out of here,
Mr. Finch.
Jem, I want you to please leave.
- No, sir.
- Jem!
I tell you, I ain't goin'.
Hey, Mr. Cunningham.
I said, "Hey, Mr. Cunningham."
How's your entailment gettin' along?
Don't you remember me,
Mr. Cunningham?
I'm Jean Louise Finch.
You brought us some hickory nuts
one morning. Remember?
We had a talk.
I went and got my daddy
to come out and thank you.
I go to school with your boy.
I go to school with Walter.
He's a nice boy.
Tell him "hey" for me,
won't you?
You know somethin',
Mr. Cunningham?
Entailments are bad.
- Entailments--
- [ Men Shuffling ]
[ Coughing ]
Atticus, I was just sayin'
to Mr. Cunningham
that entailments were bad,
but not to worry.
It takes a long time sometimes.
What's the matter?
I sure meant no harm,
Mr. Cunningham.
No harm taken, young lady.
I'll tell Walter
you said, "Hey."
Let's clear outta here.
Let's go, boys.
[ Men Murmuring ]
[ Engines Starting ]
[ Engines Revvng ]
- [ Cars Departing ]
- Now you can go home.
All of you.
I'll be there later.
Come on.
[ Tom Whispers ]
Mr. Finch, are they gone?
They've gone.
They won't bother you anymore.
[ Jem ]
'Morning, Mr. Strikes.
- How do you do?
- Ever seen so many people?
Just like on Saturday.
Where you goin'?
I can't stand it any longer.
I'm goin' to the courthouse and watch.
- You better not.
You know what Atticus said.
- I don't care if he did.
I'm not gonna miss
the most exciting thing that
ever happened in this town.
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
It's packed solid.
They're standin' all along the back.
- Reverend.
- Yes?
- Reverend Sykes,
are you going upstairs?
- Yes, I am.
[ Crowd Chattering ]
[ Chattering Continues ]
- Thank you, Brother John,
for holding my seat.
- That's okay, Reverend.
Come on, children.
Come on, come on.
[ Baby Crying ]
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
[ Murmuring Continues ]
[ Clerk ]
This court's now in session.
Everybody rise.
- [ Gavel Pounding ]
- [ Crowd Quiets ]
[ Sheriff ]
On the night of August 21,
I was just leaving my office
to go home when Bob--
Mr. Ewell came in.
Very excited he was,
and he said to get to his house
as quick as I could,
that his girl
had been raped.
I got in my car and went out
there as fast as I could.
She was pretty well beat up.
I asked her if Tom Robinson
beat her like that.
She said, yes, he had.
I asked if he'd
taken advantage of her.
She said, "Yes, he did."
That's all there was to it.
[ Prosecutor ]
Thank you.
[ Atticus ]
Did anybody call a doctor, Sheriff?
- No, sir.
- Why not?
Well, I didn't think
it was necessary.
She was pretty well beat up.
Somethin' sure happened.
It was obvious.
Now, Sheriff, you say that she was
mighty beat up. In what way?
Well, she was beaten
around the head.
There were bruises
already comin' on her arms.
She had a black eye startin'.
- Which eye?
- [ Sheriff ] Let's see.
It was her left.
Well, now, was that, uh--
That was her left,
facing you...
or looking the way
that you were?
Oh, yes, that would make it
her right eye.
It was her right eye, Mr. Finch.
Now I remember.
She was beaten up
on that side of her face.
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
Which side again, Heck?
The right side.
She had bruises
on her arms and...
she showed me her neck.
There were definite finger marks
on her gullet.
Well...
all around her neck,
at the back of her throat?
I'd say they were all around.
[ Judge ]
The witness may be seated.
[ Clerk ]
Robert E. Lee Ewell.
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
Place your hand
on the Bible, please.
Do you solemnly swear to tell the truth,
the whole truth, and nothing but
the truth, so help you God?
- I do.
- Sit down, please.
Now, Mr. Ewell,
you tell us,
just in your own words,
what happened on August 21.
[ Ewell ]
Well, that night...
I was comin' from the woods
with a load of kindlin'...
and I heard Mayella screamin'
as I got to the fence.
So I dropped my kindlin',
and I run as fast as I could,
but I run into the fence.
But when I got loose,
I run up to the window,
and I seen him
with my Mayella!
- [ Crowd Murmuring ]
- [ Gavel Pounding ]
[ Crowd Quiets ]
What did you do
after you saw the defendant?
I run around the house
tryin' to get in,
but he done run through the front door
just ahead of me!
But I seen who it was, all right!
- I seen him.
- [ Crowd Murmuring ]
And I run in the house and...
poor Mayella was layin'
on the floor squallin'.
Then I run for Mr. Tate
just as quick as I could.
Mm-hmm.
Thank you, Mr. Ewell.
- [ Crowd Laughing ]
- [ Laughing ]
Would you mind if I just,
uh, ask you a few questions, Mr. Ewell?
No, sir, Mr. Finch,
I sure wouldn't.
Folks were doin' a lot
of running that night.
You say that you ran to the house,
you ran to the window,
you ran inside, you ran to Mayella,
you ran to Sheriff Tate.
Did you, during all this running,
run for a doctor?
There wasn't no need to.
I seen who done it.
Now, Mr. Ewell, you've heard
the sheriff's testimony.
Do you agree with his description
of Mayella's injuries?
I agree with everything
Mr. Tate said.
Her eye was blacked.
She was mighty beat up,
mighty beat up.
Now, Mr. Ewell, can you, uh...
can you read and write?
Yes, sir, Mr. Finch,
I can read and I can write.
Good.
- Then will you write your name, please.
- [ Crowd Murmuring ]
Write there.
Show us.
So what's so interesting?
You're left-handed, Mr. Ewell.
What's that got to do with it, Judge?
I'm a God-fearin' man.
That Atticus Finch,
he's tryin' to take advantage of me!
You got to watch tricky lawyers
like Atticus Finch!
Quiet. Quiet, sir.
Now the witness
may take his seat.
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
[ Clerk ]
Mayella Violet Ewell.
Put your hand
on the Bible, please.
Do you solemnly swear
to tell the truth,
the whole truth and nothing
but the truth, so help you God?
Sit down, please.
[ Prosecutor ]
Now, Mayella...
suppose you tell us
just what happened, huh?
Well, sir--
[ Clears Throat ]
Sir... I was s-sittin'
on the porch...
and he come along.
There's this old chifforobe
in the yard,
and l-I said,
"You come in here, boy,
and bust up this chifforobe,
and I'll give you a nickel."
So he come on in the yard,
and I go in the house
to get him the nickel...
and I turn around
and before I know it, he's on me.
I fought and hollered...
but he had me
around the neck...
and he hit me,
again and again.
And the next thing I knew,
Papa was in the room...
a-standin' over me, hollerin',
"Who done it? Who done it?"
Thank you, Mayella.
Your witness, Atticus.
Miss Mayella,
is your father good to you?
I mean, is he easy
to get along with?
Does tolerable.
Except when he's drinking.
When he's riled...
has he ever beaten you?
My pa's never touched
a hair on my head in my life.
You say that you asked Tom to come in
and chop up a-- What was it?
A chifforobe.
Was that the first time that you ever
asked him to come inside the fence?
Yes.
Didn't you ever ask him to come
inside the fence before?
I might have.
[ Atticus ]
Can you remember any other occasion?
No.
You say, "He caught me, he choked me,
and he took advantage of me."
Is that right?
Do you remember him
beating you about the face?
No.
I don't...
[ Clears Throat ]
recollect if he hit me.
I mean, y-yes!
H-He hit me!
- He hit me!
- [ Crowd Murmuring ]
[ Murmuring Continues ]
Thank you.
Now will you identify
the man who beat you.
I most certainly will.
Sittin' right yonder.
Tom, will you stand up, please?
Let Miss Mayella
have a good long look at you.
Tom, will you
catch this, please?
Thank you.
Now, then, this time, will you please
catch it with your left hand.
I can't, sir.
[ Atticus ]
Why can't you?
I can't use
my left hand at all.
I got it caught in a cotton gin
when I was 12 years old.
All my muscles were tore loose.
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
[ Crowd Quiets ]
Is this the man
who raped you?
It most certainly is.
[ Atticus ]
How?
I don't know how.
He done it.
[ Crying ]
He just done it.
You have testified...
that he choked you
and he beat you.
You didn't say that he sneaked up
behind you and knocked you out cold,
but that you turned around...
and there he was.
Do you want to tell us
what really happened?
[ Gasps ]
I got something to say...
and then I ain't
gonna say no more!
He took advantage of me!
And if you fine,
fancy gentlemen...
ain't gonna do
nothing about it,
then you're just a bunch of lousy,
yellow, stinkin' cowards!
The whole bunch of ya!
And your fancy airs
don't come to nothin'!
Your "ma'am"-ing
and your "Miss Mayella"-ing,
it don't come to nothin',
Mr. Finch!
N-N--
[ Gasps ]
- [ Crowd Murmuring ]
- [ Mayella Gasps ]
You sit down now.
[ Murmuring Continues ]
[ Gavel Pounding ]
[ Crowd Quiets ]
Atticus.
Mr. Gilmer.
[ Clears Throat ]
The State rests, Judge.
[ Clerk ]
Tom Robinson, take the stand.
Put your hand on the Bible.
Do you solemnly swear
to tell the truth,
the whole truth and nothing
but the truth, so help you God?
- I do.
- Sit down.
Now, Tom...
were you acquainted
with Mayella Violet Ewell?
Yes, sir. I had to pass her place
going to and from the field every day.
- Is there any other way to go?
- No, sir.
None's I know of.
- And did she ever speak to you?
- Why, yes, sir.
I'd tip my hat when I'd go by.
One day she asked me
to come inside the fence...
and bust up
a chifforobe for her.
She give me the hatchet,
and I broke it up.
And then she said, "l reckon I'll
have to give you a nickel, won't l?"
And I said, "No, ma'am.
There ain't no charge."
And I went home.
Mr. Finch, that was way last spring.
Way over a year ago.
Did you ever go
on the place again?
Yes, sir.
[ Atticus ]
When?
Well, I went lots of times.
Seemed like every time
I passed by yonder,
she would have
some little something for me to do:.
chopping kindlin'
and totin' water for her.
Tom...
what happened to you...
on the evening of August 21
of last year?
Mr. Finch, I was going home
as usual that evening.
When I passed the Ewell place,
Miss Mayella were on the porch,
like she said she were.
She said for me to come there
and help her a minute.
Well, I went inside the fence,
and I looked around
for some kindlin' to work on,
but I didn't see none.
Then she said to come in the house,
she has a door needs fixin'.
So I follows her inside,
and I looked at the door...
and it looked all right.
Then she shut the door.
All the time I was wondering
why it was so quiet.
Then it come to me.
There was not a child
on the place.
And I said, "Miss Mayella,
where are the children?"
She said,
"They all gone to get ice cream."
She said it took her a year to save
seven nickels, but she'd done it.
And they'd all gone to town.
What did you say then?
Well, I said something like...
"Why, Miss Mayella,
that's right nice of you to treat 'em."
She said, "You think so?"
Well, I said, "l best be goin'."
I couldn't do nothin' for her.
And she said I could.
I asked her what.
And she said to just step
on the chair yonder...
and get that box down
from on top of the chifforobe.
So I done like she told me,
and I was reachin'...
when the next thing I knows,
she grabbed me around the legs.
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
She scared me so bad,
I hopped down and turned the chair over.
That was the only thing--
only furniture--
disturbed in the room, Mr. Finch,
I swear, when I left it.
And what happened after you
turned the chair over?
Tom?
You've sworn to tell the whole truth.
Will you do it?
What happened after that?
Mr. Finch,
I got down off the chair,
and I turned around...
and she sorta jumped on me.
She hugged me
around the waist.
She reached up and kissed me
on the face.
She said she'd never kissed
a grown man before...
and she might as well kiss me.
She says for me
to kiss her back,
and I said,
"Miss Mayella, let me outta here,"
and I tried to run.
Mr. Ewell cussed at her
from the window.
He said he's gonna kill her.
[ Atticus ]
And what happened after that?
I was runnin' so fast,
I don't know what happened.
Tom, did you rape
Mayella Ewell?
I did not, sir.
[ Atticus ]
Did you harm her in any way?
I did not, sir.
Robinson,
you're pretty good at bustin' up
chifforobes and kindlin'
with one hand, aren't ya?
Strong enough to choke the breath out
of a woman and sling her to the floor?
- I never done that, sir.
- But you're strong enough to.
- I reckon so, sir.
- Mm-hmm.
How come you so all fired anxious
to do that woman's chores?
Looks like she, she didn't
have nobody to help her.
Like I said, she--
With Mr. Ewell and seven children
on the place?
You did all this choppin' and work
out of sheer goodness, boy?
[ Chuckles ]
You're a mighty good fella, it seems.
Did all that
for not one penny?
Yes, sir.
I felt right sorry for her.
- She seemed--
- [ Gilmer Chuckling ]
You felt sorry for her?
A white woman?
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
[ Murmuring Continues ]
To begin with,
this case should never
have come to trial.
The State has not produced
one iota...
of medical evidence...
that the crime Tom Robinson
is charged with...
ever took place.
It has relied, instead,
upon the testimony
of two witnesses...
whose evidence has not only been
called into serious question...
on cross-examination,
but has been flatly contradicted
by the defendant.
There is circumstantial evidence
to indicate that...
Mayella Ewell
was beaten savagely...
by someone who led,
almost exclusively, with his left.
Tom Robinson now sits before you
having taken the oath...
with the only good hand
he possesses,
his right.
I have nothing but pity
in my heart...
for the chief witness
for the State.
She is the victim
of cruel poverty and ignorance.
But my pity...
does not extend so far...
as to her putting
a man's life at stake,
which she has done in an effort
to get rid of her own guilt.
Now I say "guilt," gentlemen,
because it was guilt
that motivated her.
She's committed no crime.
She has merely broken
a rigid and time-honored...
code of our society--
a code so severe that whoever breaks it
is hounded from our midst...
as unfit to live with.
She must destroy the evidence...
of her offense.
But what was the evidence
of her offense?
Tom Robinson, a human being.
She must put Tom Robinson
away from her.
Tom Robinson was to her
a daily reminder...
of what she did.
Now, what did she do?
She tempted a Negro.
She was white,
and she tempted a Negro.
She did something that,
in our society, is unspeakable.
She kissed a black man.
Not an old uncle,
but a strong, young Negro man.
No code mattered to her
before she broke it,
but it came crashing down
on her afterwards.
The witnesses for the State,
with the exception of the
sheriff of Maycomb County.
have presented themselves
to you gentlemen, to this court...
in the cynical confidence...
that their testimony
would not be doubted.
Confident that you gentlemen
would go along with them...
on the assumption--
the evil assumption--
that all Negroes lie,
all Negroes are basically
immoral beings,
all Negro men are not
to be trusted around our women.
An assumption that one associates
with minds of their caliber,
and which is, in itself,
gentlemen, a lie,
which I do not need
to point out to you.
And so,
a quiet, humble,
respectable Negro,
who has had the unmitigated
temerity...
to feel sorry
for a white woman,
has had to put his word
against two white people's.
The defendant is not guilty,
but somebody
in this courtroom is.
Now, gentlemen,
in this country,
our courts are the great levelers.
In our courts,
all men are created equal.
I'm no idealist
to believe firmly...
in the integrity of our courts
and of our jury system.
That's no ideal to me.
That is a living, working reality!
Now I am confident that you
gentlemen will review...
without passion...
the evidence
that you have heard,
come to a decision...
and restore this man
to his family.
In the name of God,
do your duty.
believe...
Tom Robinson.
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
How long has the jury
been out now, Reverend?
Well, let's see.
Almost two hours now.
I think that's
an awful good sign, don't you?
[ Door Opens ]
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
Court's now in session.
Everybody rise.
Gentlemen of the jury,
- have you reached a verdict?
- [ Foreman ] We have, Your Honor.
Will the defendant please rise
and face the jury?
What is your verdict?
We find the defendant
guilty as charged.
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
Gentlemen, this jury is dismissed.
[ Clerk ]
Court is adjourned.
[ Murmuring Continues ]
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
I'll go to see Helen
first thing tomorrow morning.
I told her not to be disappointed,
we'd probably lose this one.
Tom.
Yes, Mr. Finch.
Miss Jean Louise.
Miss Jean Louise,
stand up.
Your father's passin'.
[ Maudie ]
Atticus?
I-I'm sorry, Atticus.
- Well, thank you, Maudie.
- [ Car Approaching ]
Atticus, can I see you
for a minute?
Will you excuse me?
Jem?
Yes'm.
I don't know if it'll help,
but I want to say this to you.
There's some men
in this world...
who are born to do
our unpleasant jobs for us.
Your father's one of them.
- Oh, well.
- [ Car Departing ]
What's the matter, Atticus?
Tom Robinson's dead.
They were taking him
to Abbottsville...
for safekeeping.
Tom broke loose and ran.
The deputy called out
to him to stop,
and Tom didn't stop.
He shot at him to wound him
and missed his aim.
Killed him.
The deputy says...
Tom just ran like a crazy man.
The last thing I told him was not to
lose heart, that we'd ask for an appeal.
We had such a good chance.
We had more than a good chance.
I have to go out
and tell his family.
You look after
the children, Maudie.
Atticus, you want me
to go with you?
No, son, I think I'd better
go out there alone.
Atticus.
I'm goin' with you.
All right, son.
[ Brakes Squeak ]
Hello, Mr. Finch.
I'm Spence, Tom's father.
Hello, Spence.
- Is Helen here?
- Yes, sir, she's inside lyin' down,
tryin' to get
a little sleep.
We been talkin'
about the appeal, Mr. Finch.
How long do you think it'll take?
Spence, there isn't
going to be any appeal.
Not now.
Tom is dead.
Dead?
[ Atticus ]
Helen.
[ Sobbing ]
[ Continues Sobbing ]
Boy.
Go inside and tell Atticus Finch
I said to come out here.
Go on, boy.
[ Adult Scout ] By October,
things had settled down again.
I still looked for Boo
every time I went by the Radley place.
This night my mind was filled
with Halloween.
There was to be a pageant representing
our county's agricultural products.
I was to be a ham.
Jem said he would escort me
to the school auditorium.
Thus began
our longest journey together.
- Scout!
- [ Scout ] Yeah?
Will you come on?
Everybody's gone.
I can't go home like this.
Well, I'm goin'.
It's almost 10:00...
and Atticus will be
waiting for us.
All right, I'm comin'.
But I feel like a fool
walkin' home like this.
It's not my fault
you lost your dress.
I didn't lose it.
Just can't find it.
- Where are your shoes?
- I can't find them either.
- You can get 'em tomorrow.
- But tomorrow's Sunday.
You can get the janitor
to let you in. Come on.
Here, Scout. Let me hold onto you
before you break your neck.
- Jem, you don't have to hold me.
- Shh.
- What's the matter?
- Hush a minute, Scout.
I thought I heard somethin'.
Ah... come on.
Wait.
- Jem, are you trying to scare me?
- Shh.
- You know I'm too old.
- Be quiet.
- [ Dog Howling ]
- I heard an old dog bayin'.
It's not that. I hear it
when we're walking along.
When we stop,
I don't hear it anymore.
Oh, yeah, my costume rustlin'.
Halloween's got ya.
[ Rustling ]
I hear it now.
I'll bet it's just old Cecil Jacobs
tryin' to scare me.
Cecil Jacobs
is a big, wet hen!
[ Rustling ]
[ Whispers ]
Come on.
[ Rustling ]
[ Rustling Continues ]
- [ Man Shouts ]
- [ Gasps ]
[ Both Grunting ]
Run, Scout!
Run, Scout! Run! Run!
- [ Footsteps, Man Grunting ]
- [ Jem Screams ]
- [ Jem Gasping ]
- [ Man Grunting ]
[ Continues Gasping ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Screams ]
[ Men Grunting, Gasping ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Grunting, Groaning ]
[ Fighting Stops ]
[ Body Falls ]
[ Footsteps ]
[ Footsteps Passing ]
[ Door Creaks Open ]
Scout! Scout!
[ Crying ]
What happened?
I don't know.
I just don't know.
- Cal, tell Dr. Reynolds to come over.
- Yes, sir.
- You all right?
- Are you sure?
- Yes, sir.
[ Ringing ]
Sheriff Tate, please.
Atticus, is Jem dead?
No. He's unconscious.
We won't know how badly he's hurt
until the doctor gets here.
Heck? Atticus Finch.
Someone's been after my children.
He's got a bad break.
Like somebody tried
to wring his arm off.
I'll be right back, Atticus.
[ Sheriff ]
How's the boy, Doc?
He'll be all right.
Sheriff Tate.
[ Clears Throat ]
What is it, Heck?
Bob Ewell's lyin' on the ground
under that tree down yonder...
with a kitchen knife
stuck up under his ribs.
He's dead, Mr. Finch.
- Are you sure?
- [ Sheriff ] Yes, sir.
He's not gonna bother
these children anymore.
Miss Scout, you think you could
tell us what happened?
I don't know.
All of a sudden
somebody grabbed me,
knocked me down
on the ground.
Jem found me then.
Then Mr. Ewell, I reckon,
grabbed him again, and Jem hollered.
Then somebody grabbed me.
Mr. Ewell, I guess.
Somebody grabbed him...
and then I heard someone
pantin' and coughin'.
Then I saw someone
carrying Jem.
Well, who was it?
Why, there he is, Mr. Tate.
He can tell you his name.
Hey, Boo.
[ Atticus ] Miss Jean Louise,
Mr. Arthur Radley.
I believe he already knows you.
Heck, let's go out
on the front porch.
Would you like to say good night
to Jem, Mr. Arthur?
You can pet him, Mr. Arthur.
He's asleep.
You couldn't if he was awake, though.
He wouldn't let you.
Go ahead.
[ Scout ]
Let's go set in the swing, Mr. Arthur.
[ Atticus ]
Heck, l-l--
I guess that
the thing to do is, uh--
Good Lord...
I must be losin' my memory.
I can't remember
whether Jem is 12 or 13.
Anyway, it'll have to come
before the county court.
Of course, it's a clear-cut case
of self-defense.
I'll, uh-- Well, I'll run down
to the office--
Mr. Finch...
do you think Jem
killed Bob Ewell?
Is that what you think?
Your boy never stabbed him.
Bob Ewell fell on his knife.
He killed himself.
There's a black man
dead for no reason.
Now the man
responsible for it is dead.
Let the dead bury the dead
this time, Mr. Finch.
I never heard tell it was
against the law for any citizen...
to do his utmost to prevent a crime
from being committed,
which is exactly what he did.
But maybe you'll tell me
it's my duty to tell the town
all about it, not to hush it up.
You know what'll happen then.
All the ladies in Maycomb,
includin' my wife,
will be knockin' on his door
bringin' angel food cakes.
To my way of thinkin',
takin' one man,
who done you and this town
a big service,
and draggin' him with his shy ways
into the limelight--
To me, that's a sin.
It's a sin.
And I'm not about
to have it on my head.
I may not be much,
Mr. Finch,
but I'm still Sheriff
of Maycomb County,
and Bob Ewell fell on his knife.
Good night, sir.
[ Car Door Shuts, Engine Starts ]
Mr. Tate was right.
What do you mean?
Well...
it would be...
sort of like shooting
a mockingbird, wouldn't it?
Thank you, Arthur.
Thank you for my children.
[ Adult Scout ]
Neighbors bring food with death...
and flowers with sickness...
and little things in between.
Boo was our neighbor.
He gave us two soap dolls,
a broken watch and chain,
a knife...
and our lives.
One time Atticus said...
you never really knew a man
until you stood in his shoes
and walked around in them.
Just standing
on the Radley porch was enough.
The summer that had begun
so long ago had ended,
and another summer
had taken its place.
And a fall.
And Boo Radley had come out.
I was to think
of these days many times,
of Jem and Dill...
and Boo Radley
and Tom Robinson.
And Atticus.
He would be
in Jem's room all night,
and he would be there when Jem
waked up in the morning.